# Frank Muenchmeyer

### **Personal Information**

Address: 30 An Mhainistir, Claregalway, Co. Galway, Ireland

Phone: +353 87 168 4152

Email: frank.muenchmeyer@gmail.com

Nationality: German

Date of birth: 18th January 1987
Website: http://muenchmeyer.com

#### Introduction

Frank Muenchmeyer is a **senior software engineer** with experience in **agile software development**, analysis, implementation and testing of web based systems since 2008. He has a broad experience with server maintenance and cloud computing with Amazon Web Services and was also responsible for **product management** and **software architecture**.

## **Professional Experience**

## Since 04/2016 Self-employed Senior Software Engineer

Claregalway, Co. Galway, Ireland

Software development, design and implementation of new features for several clients

- Backend and frontend development with open source technologies
- Server maintenance of Ubuntu systems based on AWS or root server
- Technologies: Ruby on Rails, PHP 5.X, MySQL, HTML, CSS

#### 03/2014 - 03/2016

Senior Software Engineer at Kumukan GmbH A company of Deutsche Telekom (T-Mobile)

Product: manualONE (https://www.manualone.com)

Cologne, Germany

The company developed an App to organize customer products and to find manuals of their products. The user is also able to upload pictures of products and receipts, to add guarantee informations and generate custom products. manualONE is online available and for iOS and Android devices

- Main responsibility for the architecture of all services based on a microservice infrastructure with AWS
- Implementing of new features in the backend services with Ruby on Rails
- Organizing and working in a Scrum based team and establishing an agile product management
- Setup the test environment and integration tests with Jenkins
- Responsible for the iOS development with Objective-C
- Main Achievement: Release of the iOS App "manualONE"

## 03/2009 - 02/2014

## Senior Software Engineer at Adcloud GmbH A company of Deutsche Post DHL

Cologne, Germany

Adcloud was a performance marketing platform which has it's own adserver with realtime bidding functionality and it has it's own revenue based ad delivery

- Implementing of new services to increase the revenue based ad delivery with Ruby on Rails, CakePHP
- Implementing new algorithms and further development of the revenue based ad delivery
- Improving the scalability of our internal services and the Node.js adserver
- Product Manager/Product Owner of one Scrum based team
- Main Achievement: Google certified adserver

#### **Software Architect**

- Responsible for the architecture of all services with Amazon Web Services
- Responsible for the evaluation of new technologies

#### 07/2008 - 04/2009

## Software Engineer at GIGA Digital Televison GmbH

Cologne, Germany

GIGA was a television channel specialised on videogames with a broad amount of websites

- Developing landingpages for several clients
- Further development of the company's web-framework
- Developing of community driven games

## **Side Projects**

Since 08/2013

Software Engineer at Cheesy Meat Games (http://cheesy-meat-games.com/en/)

Cheesy Meat Games creates small games for iOS and is a small project to better understand and to learn mobile app development. The games are all available on the iOS AppStore and generate revenue

- Developing a memory based game with Objective-C
- Developing a mathematical game for kids with Objective-C

#### Education

08/2007 - 07/2008

Vocational school ("Berufsbildende Schulen III"), Magdeburg, Germany

Advanced technical college entrance qualification

Specialisation: Information Technology

08/2005 - 08/2007

Vocational school ("Berufsbildende Schulen III"), Magdeburg, Germany

Degree: Technical assistant for information technology

### **Technical Skills**



# **Additional Skills**

Languages: (

German: native speaker English: business fluent

Driving licence:

Full EU